arabou.org.sa 2009-07-03

# Arab Open University

SAB Privacy Policy

The following policy applies to users of SAB online services and is intended to explain what types of information is gathered from users and how that information is used. SAB users should also refer to SAB Policy on Acceptable use of Computer and Online Resources, which outlines SAB 's internal policy for the use and protection of resources _._

The AOU Saudi Arabia Branch (SAB) is committed to respecting your privacy. As an unregistered user, you can visit most of SAB pages without revealing any personal information. However, in order to gain access to certain systems, you must provide some personal information.Any personal information you provide will only be used by SAB to conduct official SAB business. SAB does not sell, rent, loan, trade or lease personal information collected on this site. 

To protect your privacy and prevent unauthorized use, please keep your IDs and passwords in a secure place. Also, whenever you use SAB services from a public computer, be sure to logout of the systems and close all web browser windows before you leave. 

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**

**Cookies** : A cookie is a piece of text placed on your computer by a web server. We occasionally use ''session'' cookies on some of SAB services to enhance your experience of the site and to help you move through it easily. Session cookies created on your computer by SAB servers do not contain personal information. We may use a session cookie to store a randomly generated identifying tag on your computer. Session cookies are temporary and are automatically deleted during operation of your browser or when your browser is closed. Most web browsers may be customized to refuse new cookies or delete existing cookies. Rejecting or deleting cookies may limit your ability to take advantage of some features of SAB services. 

**Logs and Network Monitoring :** We maintain log files of all access to SAB sites and also monitor network traffic for purposes of site management and security. We use this information to help diagnose problems with the server and to carry out other administrative tasks. We also use log analysis tools for such purposes as creating summary statistics to determine which information is of most interest to users, identifying system problem areas, and determining technical requirements. The following information is typically collected in these files: 

       the Internet Protocol address and domain name of your Internet Service Provider and/or  
           computer, if your computer has an IP address assigned directly to it;   
       the type of browser and operating system you use;  
       the date and time you visited SAB sites;  
       the web pages or services you accessed at SAB and amount of time spent at each page;  
           and   
       the web page from which you accessed SAB and from which any page on this site was  
           linked.  

**Information Collected by E-mail and Online Transactions**

If you send us an e-mail, we will collect your e-mail address and the contents of your message. We will use your e-mail address and the information included in your message to respond to you, to address the issues you identify, and to improve this web site. We may also use your e-mail address to notify you about updates, services, special events or activities offered by SAB. If you would prefer not to receive e-mail or other communications from SAB, contact us at support@arabou.edu.sa. 

**Disclosure of Information Collected Through our Site**

We may collect or disclose personal information without your consent if the collection or disclosure is:   
       necessary to perform SAB's statutory duties or necessary to operate a program authorized  
           by law;   
       made pursuant to a court order or by law;   
       for the purpose of validating your identity; or   
       of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in the form that cannot be  
           used to identify any particular person. 

We may also disclose personal information to law enforcement authorities to enforce SAB 's rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to SAB 's information technology assets. 

**Retention of Information Collected Through this Web Site**

We retain the information collected through SAB sites in accordance with the SAB records retention and disposition policy. The retention period differs depending on the type of information collected. Questions regarding the records retention and disposition policy should be addressed to support@arabou.edu.sa. 

**Confidentiality and Integrity** ****

We limit employee access to personal information collected through SAB sites to only those who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of personal information. 

In addition, we have implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of SAB 's information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of SAB systems as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information. 

For security purposes and to maintain the availability of SAB sites for all users, we employ software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage this web site. 

**Links to Third-Party Sites**

SAB sites contains links to, and may be linked from, sites outside of SAB sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices, terms of use, or the content of such web sites. A link to an outside web site from SAB does not constitute an endorsement or sponsorship of such web site or its content. 

**Changes to Policy and Disclaimer**

We may change this policy from time to time, and reserve the right to do so without notice. The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through SABsites. 

**Contact Information**

For questions regarding this privacy policy, please contact support@arabou.edu.sa.
